Remote access can be defined two different ways in a networking environment.
Specifically, we are either talking about remote access to networks, or we are talking about remote access to specific devices.
As we have seen in this course, remote access from a user to a corporate network is often done through a VPN, the details of which we have already covered.
Here, we do see a wireless access point with the capability of hosting a VPN, lest you think Windows Servers and other servers are the only options out there.
Let's take a look, then, at the other form of remote access, and that is Remote Desktop.
On this device, I will, from File Explorer, right-click This PC and click Properties, and then I'll click Remote settings.
There are two forms of remote access you could allow on a device.
Remote Assistance allows for someone to remotely connect to your device and perform tasks in it while you are watching. This is commonly used in help desk support.
Remote Desktop allows one to connect to the device and work, but that person has exclusive viewing and use of the device while connected to it,
unless multiple people are connected at once. In order to allow remote desktop connections, this setting needs to be enabled.
Then, one or more users need to be specified. From here, I will click Select Users. Always look to see who already has access.
And then if you want to add another user or group, click Add, type in the name of the user or group, click OK, and then this person or group,
if in possession of your IP address, can remote into this device. Be careful who you let in, obviously.